Kara Thurmond

Senior Front-end Web Developer

kthurmond.webdev@gmail.com thurmond-webdev.com Catskill, New York 917-903-2784

I am a web developer with 15+ years of experience developing and maintaining websites. Originally trained as a graphic designer, I create pixel-perfect sites that expertly bring UI/UX designers' visions to screens.

WORK EXPERIENCE -

Senior Front-End Developer

Lead Marvels, Inc - Fishkill, NY November 2017 to Present

Stack: TALL

- + Built 150+ websites in Laravel using Tailwinds CSS and Alpine
- + Converted 50+ websites from Bootstrap and jQuery to Tailwinds and Alpine
- + Daily use of PhpStorm, Git, Jira, and Slack
- + Mentor junior developers

Freelance Designer/Web Developer

January 2004 to Present

+ Build custom websites using React, WordPress, Shopify, and Squarespace

Production Director/Website-E commerce Manager

Modern Farmer Magazine- Hudson, NY November 2012 to October 2015

- + Prepared 140-page quarterly magazine for print, including prep for all artwork and Photoshop touch-ups
- + Maintained Wordpress website, including woo-commerce
- + Managed freelance writers and junior designer

Senior Graphic Designer

PR Newswire- New York, NY February 2001 - January 2004

- + Conceptualized and designed print business collateral
- + Designed and implemented HTML e-mail marketing campaigns
- + Art directed photographers and illustrators

SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS/SCSS
- PHP
- JavaScript
- Alpine.js
- Tailwinds CSS
- Laravel
- Bootstrap
- React
- MySQL
- Git
- Squarespace
- Shopify
- Wordpress
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Figma

SITE EXAMPLES

Laravel

leadmarvels.com mecpahub.org iacpahub.org smeshowcase.com

React

andrewamelinckx.com dekkerbabian.com

Squarespace

newyork-locations.com refugiopasorobles.com

WordPress

hinkeinrealty.com davidbellnovels.com

EDUCATION

BA in Philosophy Mary Washington University Fredericksburg, VA